Zain Ul Abidin

Brooklyn, NY 11230 • E: khzainulabidin@gmail.com **GitHub:** @khzainulabidin • **LinkedIn:** @khzainulabidin • **Portfolio:** View Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hardworking, disciplined **Full Stack Web Developer** with 5 years of experience in full stack web development and graphic design. Able to create effective, attractive digital business solutions. Detailed and efficient, with an international perspective. Collaborative and friendly; excel at working both independently as well as part of a team. Passionate about building world class web applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, and SQL

Databases: MongoDB, and MySQL

Frameworks & Libraries: React JS, Node JS, Express JS, jQuery, Material UI, Ant, SASS, and Bootstrap

Tools: Git, Jest, JetBrains IDEs, Visual Studio Code, MS Office, Adobe Illustrator & XD

EDUCATION

COMSATS University 2017 – 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

KEY PROJECTS

TriPlanner – A smarter way to plan your trip | 2021

A web application to facilitate the tourists and to bridge the gap between tourists and businesses. Tourists can generate comprehensive trip plans based on multiple stops (destinations), add their friends into the plan, manage budget, and book rooms. On the other hand, hotels can automate the whole process of managing their hotel.

Technologies: JavaScript, React JS, Express JS, MongoDB, Google Maps Platform, HTML, CSS, and Material UI.

Taskoo | 2020

A freelancing website designed for a client where users can offer and purchase services/tasks in a wide range of categories.

Technologies & Tools: JavaScript, React JS, HTML, CSS, React Ant, and APIs Integration.

Portfolio Website | 2020

My own portfolio website to display my web design and graphic design projects.

Technologies: JavaScript, React JS, HTML, CSS, and SASS.

WORK HISTORY

FIVERR 2015 - 2020

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer | 2018 - 2020

- Participate in the design and creation of scalable websites
- Write clean, functional front-end and back-end code, test and fix bugs or other coding issues

Freelance Graphic Designer | 2015 - 2019

- Plan and illustrate concepts and prepare finished art
- Create a wide range of graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and websites